Guide to the New York City Taxicab Industry Research Files,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
New York City Taxicab Industry Research Files,
1966-2005
[Bulk Dates: 1978-1986]
Rogoff, Edward G., 1951-
2.94 linear ft. (4 document boxes, 3 index card boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#1462
6865079
The collection is primarily comprised of materials consulted by Edward Rogoff during research for his dissertation on regulatory issues and the New York City Taxicab industry. The records also chronicle Rogoff’s ongoing interest in related taxicab agency issues and affairs.
Historical Note
The collection was created by Edward Rogoff, professor of Management and Academic Director of the Lawrence N. Field Center for Entrepreneurship and Small Business at Baruch College. Rogoff began compiling these materials during research for his dissertation The Regulation of the New York City Taxicab Industry and continued to collect items as his interest and involvement in industry issues grew.
Scope and Content
The collection contains records related to the New York City taxicab industry, particularly pertaining to regulatory issues in the 1970s and 1980s. The materials describe New York City taxicab agency rules and regulations and taxi driver perspectives and concerns. In addition to publications and records, the collection also includes notes written by Rogoff chronicling his experience driving a taxicab on the streets of New York City, notes from interviews with taxicab drivers and transcripts of testimony given by Rogoff at various committee meetings. The collection consists of reports, articles, brochures, correspondence, notes, memoranda, proposals, and press releases.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in two series.
Series I: Administrative Files, 1966-2005
Series II: Published Materials, 1974-2003
Subjects
New York (N.Y.).--Taxi and Limousine Commission.; Rogoff, Edward G., 1951-; Taxicabs--Economic aspects.; Taxicabs--New York (State)--New York.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 1 through 5. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
Edward Rogoff Gift, 2008
- Series I: Administrative Files, 1966-2005
  Series I contains material consulted by Rogoff for dissertation research and records created by Rogoff, other individuals, and agencies pertaining to the New York City taxicab industry. The series includes information related to the New York City Taxi and Limousine Commission, in the form of staff correspondence, meeting agenda, and memoranda, which provide a sense of the topics discussed at hearings and meetings. Rogoff’s correspondence, notes and interview transcripts offer an understanding of his research process and findings. The records also provide information on New York City Taxicab Driver Unions and their views.
  Boxes 5, 6, and 7 house index cards containing bibliographic citations of articles (1900-1970) related to the New York City taxicab industry.
  - Correspondence, 1972-2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Financial Reports, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hearings, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Interviews, 1976-1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Memoranda and Notices, 1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Metropolitan Taxicab Board of Trade, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - New York City Taxi Drivers Union, undated, 1976-1998, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 7 to 8)
  - New York City Taxi and Limousine Commission
    - Correspondence, 1977-1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Hearings, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Memoranda, 1979-2001 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Press Release, 1974-1986, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Proposals, 1980-2001 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Notes
    - General, undated 1972-1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Bibliographic
      - General, undated (Box 5)
      - Covering undated, 1935-1937 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Covering undated, 1900s-1960s (Box 6)
      - Covering undated, 1960s-1970s (Box 7)
  - Press Releases, 1965-1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Proposals, 1978-1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Testimonies, 1980-2001 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Unpublished Articles, undated 1981-2000 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Series II: Published Material, 1974-2003
  Series II consists of material published by various New York governmental agencies, including the New York City Taxi and Limousine Commission, and other organizations and individuals. Reports in this series focus on topical statistics, analyses and recommendations, published by city agencies and outside sources. The series consists of reports, articles, booklets, and brochures. Also included are annual reports, fact books, publications for taxicab drivers and a copy of Rogoff’s dissertation The Regulation of the New York City Taxicab Industry.
  - Booklets and Brochures, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Magazines, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Reports
    - General, 1974-2003, (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 3 to 6)
    - New York City Agencies, 1978-1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - New York City Agencies, 1984-2003 ( 5 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1 to 5)
  - Rogoff, Edward
    - Articles, 1980-1998 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Dissertation, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)